Arizona Mohair Growers Association Papers, 1934-1951
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections
Arizona Mohair Growers Association, 1934-1951
AZ 126
Arizona Mohair Growers Association
Correspondence, financial records, minutes of meetings, reports, statistics, photographs, articles and newspaper clippings relating to the organization of the association, its history, activities in promoting the mohair industry in Arizona, and its association with similar State, national, and Federal agencies in the use of land, grazing districts, stock driveways, marketing of mohair, sale of goat meat, and the eradication of predatory animals.
.8 linear feet
University of Arizona Libraries, Special Collections University of Arizona PO Box 210055 Tucson, AZ 85721-0055 Phone: 520-621-6423 Fax: 520-621-9733 URL:http://speccoll.library.arizona.edu/
Restrictions
None
Historical Note
The Arizona Mohair Growers Association, based in Prescott; formed to promote the mohair industry and study rangeland use and grazing.
Organization
This collection is organized into two series:
Series I: Business Records, 1934-1951
Series II: Business Correspondence, 1934-1949
Scope and Content Note
Correspondence, financial records, minutes of meetings, reports, statistics, photographs, articles and newspaper clippings relating to the organization of the association, its history, activities in promoting the mohair industry in Arizona, and its association with similar State, national, and Federal agencies in the use of land, grazing districts, stock driveways, marketing of mohair, sale of goat meat, and the eradication of predatory animals. Photographs, used for publicity, show angora goat herds, probably in the Prescott, Ariz. area.
Access Terms
Arizona Mohair Growers Association -- Records and correspondence
Goats -- Arizona
Mohair industry -- Arizona
Grazing -- Arizona
Rangelands -- Arizona
Correspondence
Photoprints
Photographs
Bills (financial)
Container List
- Series I: Business Records, 1934-1951
  - Constitution, By-laws, Membership Lists, Various Historical Items. 1934-1951 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes of Meetings. 1936-1948 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Official Notices. 1936-1947 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Ballots and Correspondence Regarding Dispersal of Funds. 1947, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Arizona State Land Code (proposed changes, correpsondence). 1939-1942 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Publicity (articles, clippings). 1936-1951 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Photographs. 1936-1951 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bank of Arizona-Statements, Checks. 1937-1943 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Treasurer's Records, Ledger. 1936-1946 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Bills. 1936-1943 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- Series II: Business Correspondence, 1934-1949
  - Correspondence-General. 1936-1949 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence-Goat Range Survey. 1936-1941 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence-Grazing Districts. 1936-1942 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence-Stock Driveway. 1939-1940 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence-Biological Survey. 1938-1948 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence-San Carlos Strip. 1939-1941 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence-Marketing Goats (includes material on 1934 drought). 1934-1942 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence-Marketing Mohair. 1934-1945 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence-Miscellaneous Marketing Records (spring clip, shipment records, meat market clippings, legal papers, statistical charts, survey of mohair markets). 1937-1939 (Box 2, Folder 9)